Friends, we regularly review the funds you comment on on a regular basis on the Pooji Guide YouTube channel.
So today we are going to review another small cap fund
in detail.  I am
talking about Mahindra Manual Life
Salcap Fund.  We
will analyze this fund from all perspectives and at the
end of the video I will also share my conclusion regarding this fund.
If we first
look at the AMC profile of this mutual fund,
it comes from Mahindra Manual Mutual Fund.
This fund house is a 9-year-old fund
with a total
asset size of ₹29,590 crore being managed.  Meaning,
this fund house is
definitely a little new compared to other fund houses.  If we
talk about the launch of Mahindra manual salc fund,
it has been launched in 2022.  That means
this fund is a new fund in the small cap category.  The
fund's benchmark follows the BS 250
Small Cap TRI.  If we
look at the latest AUM of the fund, it is ₹453 crore.  This
means that in a very short time the AIM of the fund has become
quite good.  If we look at the
expense ratio of the direct plan of the fund,
it will be 0.44%.  Whereas
in category average it is 0.63%.  This means that
this fund is going to be slightly cheaper than other funds in the category.   At the
same time, if you
withdraw your money within 3 months of investment, then
you will have to pay an exit load of 1%.
The fund is being managed by Mr. Manish Lodha from 2022
, Mr. Vishal Jaju from 2024 and
Mr. Krishna Sangvi.
So, if we look at it, Manish Lodha is a very
experienced fund manager here.
Who has also worked with fund houses like HSBC and Kotak Mahindra.
Let's move ahead and look at the fund's
returns.  The
fund's returns in the last two years have been 21.14%.
Whereas in the last one year it is negative
8.56%.  If the
returns of this fund are compared with some other funds of the same category, then the
returns of Tata Salcap Fund in the last 2 years are 18.58% and
in the last one year it is negative 5.04%.  If we
look at the returns of Inveso India Salcap Fund, it is 25.78% in the last 2 years
and 90% in the last one year.  If we
look at the returns of Axis Salcap Fund, it
is 17.90% in the last 2 years and 38% in the last one year.  So overall,
we do not have
much data available here to value the returns of the fund,
but
still the start of the fund can be considered good.
However, this fund has still fallen slightly more
in the last one year compared to other small cap funds.
Friends, it has
not been 3 years since this fund was launched.
So its risk ratios are
not available here.  We can directly
see its portfolio.  In which you will
see the number of stocks 68.  The
weightage of the top 10 stocks will be 23.79%.  This
means that the portfolio has been
diversified very well.
If we look at the PB ratio of the portfolio,
it is 3.35 and the PE ratio is 28.83.   At the
same time, if we look at the average PE of the small cap index for the last
10 years, it comes out to be 30.  That is, it can be
said
that the valuation of the fund is still reasonable.
If we look at the present cash holding of the fund,
it is 2.83%.  That means the fund is
holding that much money in cash.   If we
look at the turnover ratio of the fund,
it is 100%.  This means that this fund
removes all the stocks from the portfolio in 1 year.
Meaning that the conclusion coming out is
that this fund is of an aggressive nature.  In
which this portfolio focuses on
generating returns by making significant changes in stocks.
If we
look at the asset allocation of the fund, it has
invested 4.81% in large cap companies.
21.80% is invested in mid cap companies
and 70.56% in small cap companies.
So, the asset
allocation of the fund here is almost
in line with the category average.  However, the
fund has slightly higher exposure to mid-cap stocks.
If we look at the sector wise allocation of the fund,
it has highest exposure in financial, consumer
staples, capital goods, metals & mining
and healthcare.
Where they have not taken allocation of
more than 20% in any specific sector.
Which can be
considered very good for a small cap fund.
Friends, you
can see the list of top 20 stocks of this salc fund here.
Friends, this fund is
a new fund in the small cap category.  So, here
new fund age risk is present in this fund.  This means that
we have limited data and it is a
bit difficult to find out the actual strategy of the fund.  Nevertheless, based
on the analysis done, it is clear
that this fund is a
small cap fund following an aggressive strategy.  In which this
portfolio
focuses on creating rates by making frequent changes in stocks.
Due to which we will not get to see
good downside protection in this small cap fund.
Due to this reason,
this fund can be a bit volatile in nature, making
it
a better choice for aggressive investors
rather than those looking for a stable small cap fund.
So friends, this was a
detailed review of Mahindra Manual Salcap Fund.
If you liked this information,
then please like, comment and share the video.
Also, please subscribe to this channel.
So friends, let's
meet again with some new information.
[music]